<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>SR(A)WN</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/</link><description>Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter</description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>SR2015 Issue 03</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2015/2014-06-23-srawn-03.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2015 — 3&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the third issue of the Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings-on across SR. This is a bit of an experiment, so if you have feedback or think we've missed something, feel free to reply to this thread. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened items&lt;/strong&gt; are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since exams are now over, Peter has resumed his &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/IE-xKIQgWOY/discussion"&gt;&amp;quot;Learning by doings&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; idea, using Google Hangouts to perform tasks along with other blueshirts. &lt;strong&gt;Ideas for topics of these doings would be welcome&lt;/strong&gt;. [0]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peter has created &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/wiki/SRComp"&gt;Trac pages&lt;/a&gt; about the new competition software (that was used at the 2014 competition). [1]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our treasurers sent out the cheques covering SR2014 expenses went to volunteers and teams recently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Certificates were organised and sent out by Howard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/wiki/ParticipantStats"&gt;Participant stats&lt;/a&gt; for SR2014 were added to Trac by Rob. [2]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jon Bartlett is finalising the &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/7EFZ80qs9Q8/discussion"&gt;child protection policy-related documents&lt;/a&gt;. [3]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Murray has posted the results of last weeks doing, &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-game/jYHb2FoVizg/discussion"&gt;reviews of the current game ideas&lt;/a&gt;. [4]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alistair has been working on &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/i4C1fa4g4ow/discussion"&gt;revising the regulations&lt;/a&gt; in the game rules to condense them down and make them clearer. [5]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Merging competition and development robot modes was briefly discussed and the conclusion was that the modes will be kept separate. The discussion, however, has led to the creation of a &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/wiki/Competition/RobotModes"&gt;Trac page&lt;/a&gt;. [6]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andy Busse has requested that &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/RCd0OKoEkFc/discussion"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;volunteers who are interesting in taking part in the summer school should contact him&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. [7]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rob is making progress on the &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/dElFvRLIWo8/discussion"&gt;charity situation&lt;/a&gt;. [8]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comments that various people have made about the 2014 competition have been collated into a &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/wiki/2014/Competition/WashUp"&gt;Trac page&lt;/a&gt;. [9]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The previous issue can be found &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/vGIC6Wy9Kg4/discussion"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. [10]&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2015/2014-06-23-srawn-03.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2015 Issue 02</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2015/2014-07-02-srawn-02.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2015 — 4&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the fourth issue of the Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings-on across SR. This is a bit of an experiment, so if you have feedback or think we've missed something, feel free to reply to this thread. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two internships are running over the summer. Giorgos Karatziolas will be working on &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-devel/_GiVdXIvGO4/discussion"&gt;making a battery fuel guage&lt;/a&gt; [0] and Tom Leese will be working on the interface on the tablets as part of the new SR2015 kit (list post to come shortly).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Certificates have &lt;em&gt;definitely&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/msg/srobo/f8ps8rKfeE0/IeYUpzcAuWcJ"&gt;been sent out now&lt;/a&gt; [1].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The game submission deadline is almost with us: &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-game/icdyUesc5XU/discussion"&gt;discussion ends on the 4th and voting on the 9th&lt;/a&gt; [2]. &lt;strong&gt;Anyone who has a game submission should take the time to &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-game/YHTqEKftaS0/discussion"&gt;clarify the final version&lt;/a&gt; [3] of their game on the list.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Smallpeice is taking place in the last week of July and &lt;strong&gt;any extra volunteers would be helpful&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The steering minutes from the latest committee meeting (23rd July) &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/cgit/steering-minutes.git/tree/2013-2014/2014-06-23/minutes.txt"&gt;have been placed into Git&lt;/a&gt; [4]. Key points to take away include: aiming for 81 teams and schools like the idea of having to travel to get to a kickstart to encourage the students.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Signing up exists in some form or other, and &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/VAfEPOmplOY/discussion"&gt;discussion is ongoing&lt;/a&gt; [5].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jeremy has posted the &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/t9gVNWYxF6o/discussion"&gt;teacher feedback he has received&lt;/a&gt; [6], and that feedback is generally very good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sam has performed some analysis on the competition server logs and performed some extra benchmarking to &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/IeUe20rdnwY/discussion"&gt;produce a report&lt;/a&gt; [7].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jeremy has reported that a line of code with &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-devel/s03XxFcpgCA/discussion"&gt;17,000 characters causes pylint 0.26 to hang&lt;/a&gt; [8], solutions include enforcing a line-length limit or simply updating pylint.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Lilafisch, Tyler Ward and Tom Leese for contributing. The previous issue can be found &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/f8ps8rKfeE0/discussion"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; [9].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[0] https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-devel/_GiVdXIvGO4/discussion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] https://groups.google.com/d/msg/srobo/f8ps8rKfeE0/IeYUpzcAuWcJ&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-game/icdyUesc5XU/discussion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[3] https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-game/YHTqEKftaS0/discussion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[4] https://www.studentrobotics.org/cgit/steering-minutes.git/tree/2013-2014/2014-06-23/minutes.txt&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[5] https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/VAfEPOmplOY/discussion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[6] https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/t9gVNWYxF6o/discussion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[7] https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/IeUe20rdnwY/discussion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[8] https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-devel/s03XxFcpgCA/discussion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9] https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/f8ps8rKfeE0/discussion&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2015/2014-07-02-srawn-02.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2015 Issue 05</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2015/2014-07-17-srawn-05.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2015 — 5&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the fifth issue of the Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings-on across SR. This is a bit of an experiment, so if you have feedback or think we've missed something, feel free to reply to this thread. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2015/2014-07-17-srawn-05.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2015 Issue 08</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2015/2014-10-09-srawn-08.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2015 — 8&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the eighth issue of the Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings-on across SR. If you have feedback or think we've missed something, feel free to reply to this thread. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/wiki/2015/Teams"&gt;53 teams are now signed up&lt;/a&gt; for the competition; two teams have unfortunately dropped out already.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creation of accounts before Kickstart &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-devel/NIqflkL6JhQ/discussion"&gt;has worked out well&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The server &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-devel/1-jc3_WhzgQ/discussion"&gt;has been moved&lt;/a&gt; over to a more powerful Linode VPS called 'saffron' — Rob won a doughnut for correctly guessing the server naming scheme, which was Firefly!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/IyDYyHGGVjs/discussion"&gt;discussion on electrical safety&lt;/a&gt; has been started on the list and progress will continue in a &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/ticket/2582"&gt;trac ticket&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Student Robotics was &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/30PrnzJws8Q/discussion"&gt;mentioned in a recently edition of The Daily Telegraph&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bristol and Southampton held their Newbie Doings for this year:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Southampton:&lt;/em&gt; We had cake! To make entry to mentoring easier we are trying a new concept: assign personal tutor to newbie.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bristol:&lt;/em&gt; Large turnout at the newbie Doing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peter &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/2DJJgpCf9yg/discussion"&gt;proposed a number of ways&lt;/a&gt; to get better publicity, including organising the news better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First cuts of the videos produced by Olly during Smallpeice are available at their respective trac tickets: &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/ticket/2588"&gt;State Machines&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/ticket/2585"&gt;Inputs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/ticket/2584"&gt;Program Design&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/ticket/2583"&gt;Debugging&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SR testing: Southampton spent the last doings developing &lt;a href="https://github.com/Muzer/sr-test-scripts"&gt;test scripts&lt;/a&gt; for cameras, motor boards and ruggueduinos; these scripts are now all functioning and testing with them will finish soon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Batteries are being tested and recharged ready for shipping.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assembly of new boards into cases has started in Oxford.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alistair, Giorgos and Lilafisch are getting the micro games finished and Giorgos will announce a doing for assembling the bits that need to go to the different Kickstarts, instructions for blueshirts are being written.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chris K is making progress on the rules, &lt;strong&gt;please help by reviewing&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/query?group=status&amp;amp;milestone=SR2015+Kickstart"&gt;trac milestone for Kickstart&lt;/a&gt; is rather empty, &lt;strong&gt;please help by filling in what is missing!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who turned up at the doing yesterday for contributing (apologies for being unable to name people directly). The previous issue can be found &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/y-IAVCfbKj0/discussion"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2015/2014-10-09-srawn-08.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2015 Issue 09</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2015/2014-10-24-srawn-09.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2015 — 9&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the ninth issue of the Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings-on across SR. If you have feedback or think we've missed something, feel free to reply to this thread. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AAARRRRRRRRGGGGGGGGGGGGHHHHH Kickstart tomorrow!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The IDE has been &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/ticket/2626"&gt;updated for the new kit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kit for this year has been finished and was packed &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/ticket/2616"&gt;shipped to Kickstarts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The rules are &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/ticket/2623"&gt;live and ready for shipping&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/wiki/2015/Teams"&gt;team list was finalised&lt;/a&gt; and there is a &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/vHJ5PZeWEmE/discussion"&gt;recruitment situation report&lt;/a&gt; available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The software running on the brain board has been &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/cgit/brain/sr-robot.git/"&gt;pushed to git&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saffron server monitoring has been re-enabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-devel/q5ICs8f53hk/discussion"&gt;tablet interface&lt;/a&gt; exists and has been testing with the new kit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Epic Vault Doing of &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/IWSxXeRkuCA/discussion"&gt;much labelling&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lots of kit testing and &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/d/topic/srobo/e0XiR6YdbVs/discussion"&gt;all the kit boxes have been packed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A substantial amount of &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/K1i147mL84k/discussion"&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; has been written for SR2015, &lt;strong&gt;although there is plenty that could be improved&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/4lpZD-tLafw/discussion"&gt;London Kickstart&lt;/a&gt; is happening - volunteers should arrive before 09:50.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/ggnE-Jrey-Y/discussion"&gt;Southampton Kickstart&lt;/a&gt; is happening - arrive at 08:00 at building 32 and bring kettle if convenient.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bristol Kickstart is happening.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Batteries were unable to be shipped with the pallet so they are being transported separately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Screwdrivers and wirestripper shipping has occurred and have definitely arrived in &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/MTpP6wLcHJE/discussion"&gt;Southampton&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The videos Olly has been producing have been put on hiatus &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/V4siqbGbc7A/discussion"&gt;due to unfortunate circumstances&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Account creation is &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-devel/NIqflkL6JhQ/discussion"&gt;ongoing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Harry Cutts, Freddie Nash, Tom Leese, Alistair Lynn, Tyler Ward and Andy Barrett-Sprot for working on this issue. Previous issue can be found &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/lINzZhChXck/discussion"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2015/2014-10-24-srawn-09.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2015 Issue 11</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2015/2014-11-26-srawn-11.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN — 11 (Tom's Birthday) (Happy birthday!)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the eleventh issue of the Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings-on across SR. If you have feedback or think we've missed something, feel free to reply to this thread. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Trac wiki was cleaned and brought up to date at a &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/X6VwSraJNgM/discussion"&gt;recent Southampton doing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python tools port &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/effMxq6Is6g/discussion"&gt;is still happening&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/wiki/DevScripts#BetaInstallationMethod"&gt;testing the new tools&lt;/a&gt; would be very helpful&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/lhzCAXbbU0I/discussion"&gt;Revision 2 of the rules&lt;/a&gt; has been shipped.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tech days have been &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/key_dates"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; for both Southampton and Bristol.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;srweb has been updated to use &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-devel/NSBzFGK1vdg/discussion"&gt;Smarty 3&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alistair put together &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-devel/tm3OXQ-ILZQ/discussion"&gt;a script to watch Gerrit and update trac tickets&lt;/a&gt; when they get fixed in commits following standard fix message convention.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-devel/FlDvQ3p6Thg/discussion"&gt;Fritter&lt;/a&gt; is now live and running in production. Written by Peter, it enables a large number of emails to be sent out without appearing as spam.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/BmpSw75E9Fk/discussion"&gt;improved Child Protection policy&lt;/a&gt; has been outlined and &lt;strong&gt;desperately requires feedback&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The towel-throws mechanism is still under discussion on the srobo-game list. No resolution is forthcoming, &lt;strong&gt;more input would be appreciated&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The steering committee will be meeting this December to discuss Student Robotics &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/n5OWoI7Azsk/discussion"&gt;becoming a charity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The assembly of the Kit is now documented &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/docs/kit/"&gt;in the Docs&lt;/a&gt; and an &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vhZjjCdhVE0"&gt;assembly video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is now a tool to generate Trac tickets for yearly &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/cgit/recurring-tasks.git/"&gt;recurring tasks&lt;/a&gt;. This has now been used to generate the &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/milestone/SR2015%20Competition"&gt;Trac tickets for the 2015 competition&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We are starting to collect mentoring times for all the teams, which are documented on the &lt;a href="http://trac.srobo.org/wiki/2015/Teams"&gt;Teams page on Trac&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Team Updates:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;QMC &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/forum/viewtopic.php?f=9&amp;amp;t=210"&gt;broke a power board&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are 18 teams who have set their &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/teams/"&gt;team status&lt;/a&gt; on the website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CCR are &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/forum/viewtopic.php?f=10&amp;amp;t=194"&gt;looking at using an I&amp;lt;sup&amp;gt;2&amp;lt;/sup&amp;gt;C motor controller&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Tom Leese, Giorgos Karatziolas, Freddie Nash, lilafisch, and Alistair Lynn for contributing. The previous issue can be found &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/EkuoF2V2Mbc/discussion"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2014 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2015/2014-11-26-srawn-11.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2015 Issue 12</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2015/2014-12-17-srawn-12.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2015 — 12&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the twelfth issue of the Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings‐on across Student Robotics. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Internal Updates:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/xJ0elYMIDpo/discussion"&gt;tech days happened&lt;/a&gt;, with &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/v4F9fRbgxoQ"&gt;some interesting results&lt;/a&gt;—no teams turned up at Southampton. Attendance has &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/wiki/Tech%20Days/Attendance"&gt;started to be recorded&lt;/a&gt; as a result of this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Student Robotics was &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/KIWW78ZOZcs"&gt;shown off at Southampton to prospective students&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/vCH5G4rROAQ/discussion"&gt;update on the charity situation&lt;/a&gt; was posted. The charity application has been submitted and there has been a large objection to this, leading to two committee members announcing that they will resign.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team QMC were &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/ticket/2796#comment:6"&gt;given a new power board&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Numerous purchasing tickets were closed. [^0]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://studentrobotics.org/cgit/tools.git/tree/?h=new-tools"&gt;Work on the tools continues&lt;/a&gt; and should be &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/wiki/DevScripts#BetaInstallationMethod"&gt;ready for public testing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; shortly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some of the &lt;strong&gt;camera documentation has been &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/ticket/2808"&gt;discovered to be wrong&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Duplicate asset codes &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-devel/yF29dHWCOmQ/discussion"&gt;were discovered&lt;/a&gt; in the inventory&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A decision on &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-devel/9YRmhft8FVg/discussion"&gt;how to proceed in terms of product searching&lt;/a&gt; in the tools has &lt;strong&gt;yet to be made&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/msg/srobo-devel/NIqflkL6JhQ/oXXsagdCW0MJ"&gt;update on team account creation&lt;/a&gt; was posted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An issue in the power board relating to I&amp;lt;sup&amp;gt;2&amp;lt;/sup&amp;gt;C &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-devel/SIKPfj8t_lU/discussion"&gt;has been fixed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Output current reading measurements &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-devel/f0IV0kxPCSE/discussion"&gt;have been taken&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/gerrit/#/c/1988/"&gt;update to the rules&lt;/a&gt; fixing references to SR2014 &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/gerrit/#/c/2004/"&gt;has been uploaded&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Team Updates:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HRS have been &lt;a href="https://studentrobotics.org/forum/viewtopic.php?f=11&amp;amp;t=231"&gt;experiencing problems&lt;/a&gt; with the current limit on the power board.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HRS may have a &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/ticket/2809"&gt;problem with their camera&lt;/a&gt;. They discovered that they &lt;a href="https://studentrobotics.org/forum/viewtopic.php?f=10&amp;amp;t=221"&gt;could not take photos at certain resolutions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CLY have been getting &lt;a href="https://studentrobotics.org/forum/viewtopic.php?f=11&amp;amp;t=222"&gt;a mysterious beeping noise&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Tom Leese, Tyler Ward and Alistair Lynn for working on this issue. The previous issue can be found &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/9CQw1i0fT3w/discussion"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[^0] See tickets closed on 6th December in the &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/timeline"&gt;timeline&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2015/2014-12-17-srawn-12.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2015 Issue 13</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2015/2015-01-14-srawn-13.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2015 — 13&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the thirteenth issue of the Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings‐on across Student Robotics. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Internal updates:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Committee steering elections are coming up. &lt;strong&gt;Applicants for roles must do so via &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/#%21topic/srobo/pIsqEwqSmfI"&gt;the mailing list&lt;/a&gt; by 26th January.&lt;/strong&gt; Steering committee roles on Trac have been &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/wiki/Committee2/SteeringRoles"&gt;updated&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/gerrit/#/q/status:open+project:server/puppet,n,z"&gt;Various patches&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;code&gt;srweb&lt;/code&gt; which move submodules to Puppet have been updated and require reviewing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/prophile/srweb-jekyll"&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; is being &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/#%21topic/srobo-devel/OED7yj0UgfY"&gt;worked on&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-devel/UhwUkSYaIq4/discussion"&gt;Further updates to the power board&lt;/a&gt; have been worked on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flag design and prototyping for SR2015 &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-devel/6iJl04Lv-WE/discussion"&gt;has happened&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The improvements to the tools have &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-devel/NHr2Rmdbj4M/discussion"&gt;reached feature completion&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;People should upgrade to check their workflow hasn't been broken.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/qkyUcML8fLQ/discussion"&gt;More responses&lt;/a&gt; relating to charity objections have been posted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Team updates:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More teams have been &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/forum/viewtopic.php?f=14&amp;amp;t=224"&gt;asking questions&lt;/a&gt; about the mascots on the top of the flags.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Tom Leese, Andrew Barrett-Sprot, Samson Danziger and Henry Kennedy for working on this issue. The previous issue can be found &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/PuvcxMn7kO0/discussion"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2015/2015-01-14-srawn-13.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2015 Issue 14</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2015/2015-01-28-srawn-14.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2015 — 14&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the fourteenth issue of the Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings‐on across Student Robotics. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Internal updates:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mentoring in Southampton &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/wiki/2015/Teams?action=diff&amp;amp;version=70"&gt;has started&lt;/a&gt;, a bit later than usually though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The first Tech Day in Munich happened at MAI, who have built an arena for testing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Competition Software now runs on &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/gerrit/#/q/status:merged+topic:python3,n,z"&gt;Python 3&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/gerrit/#/q/status:merged+topic:setuptools,n,z"&gt;uses Setuptools&lt;/a&gt; for installation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SRBot has &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/gerrit/#/c/2026/"&gt;been replaced&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="http://willie.dftba.net/"&gt;Willie&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sign-ups for a committee position &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/pIsqEwqSmfI/discussion"&gt;have now closed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/FDne6bgop_I/discussion"&gt;Various updates&lt;/a&gt; to Southampton venue ideas for the competition have happened.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/I753QS1HuS8/discussion"&gt;date hold on Newbury Racecourse&lt;/a&gt; as a competition venue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;first&lt;/em&gt; Volunteer Activity Day is &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/9IjBmI7QwgI/discussion"&gt;happening this week&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A summary of the possible results from the committee vote has &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/msg/srobo/J9-WZsp45FA/_Y-Ks05sV6YJ"&gt;been posted&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Committee Vote:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following people have applied for positions on the committee:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Community: &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/-oHZMtjuLtc/discussion"&gt;Tom Leese&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engineering: &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/2u6ECW6-91k/discussion"&gt;Rich Barlow&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/dR3_Cf7RMz0/discussion"&gt;Peter Law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Events: &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/G1GXxXeHSg4/discussion"&gt;Lilafisch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/ctVA9mYTURU/discussion"&gt;Sam Phippen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public Interaction: &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/IFWIwkmuZOI/discussion"&gt;Harry Cutts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Schools &amp;amp; Mentoring: &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/_2Gjx1mC6CY/discussion"&gt;Jon Bartlett&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/ewQ-8wf8CN8/discussion"&gt;Jeremy Morse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sponsor Interaction: &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/x_UDiPfXBdA/discussion"&gt;Andy Busse&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/85QpxjCIuGQ/discussion"&gt;Rob Spanton&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Team updates:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peter Symonds https://pscrobotics.wordpress.com/2015/01/16/cheeky-build-photo/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;QMC http://teamqmc.esy.es/uncategorized/update-2112015/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collyers http://collyersstudentrobotics.blogspot.co.uk/2015/01/keeping-everything-clean-and-tidy.html&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cornwall College Saltash http://ccsrobotics.over-blog.com/2015/01/week-8-recapping-the-code.html&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brockenhurst have a robot base and a good idea of how they're going to build the rest of it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taunton do not have a robot yet, but they have been prototyping on last year's robot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bishop Wordsworth School have not assembled a robot, but they have started programming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;South Wilts Grammar School have a robot base with wheels and lots of code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First time mentor, Andy Barrett-Sprot, says &amp;quot;I expected it to be more like teaching, but it was more about supporting the teams, I think that's a good idea because it doesn't waste their time.&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Tom Leese, Alistair Lynn, Lilafisch and Murray Colpman for working on this issue. The previous issue can be found &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/W3bkdK2vXVE/discussion"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2015/2015-01-28-srawn-14.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2015 Issue 15</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2015/2015-02-11-srawn-15.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2015 — 15&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the fifteenth issue of the Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings‐on across Student Robotics. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Internal Updates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A hangout to discuss the competition software occured, with various outcomes. Tickets have been created and anyone can feel free to pick up any task. Already bugs and features are being submitted to Gerrit and merged in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bristol hosted its second tech day—33 competitors turned up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Part of the 'How to Help' page on the website has been rewritten to make it more readable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steering committee vote happened and the results have been published.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A discussion tinker time at the competition has been initiated and is on going.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Funding has been received from Motorola.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;first&lt;/em&gt; Volunteer Activity Day happened and was a great success.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Investigations into whether keeping Git objects in a database is any better for the IDE.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Research into improved match scheduling at the competition has happened.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A private PyPI has been set up to putu any Pip and Setuptools based Python projects we have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A commit to merge the new tools branch back into the tools has been submitted to Gerrit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The power board now has firmware capable of playing sounds via the on board piezo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Steering Committee Results&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Community: Tom Leese&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engineering: Richard Barlow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Events: Sam Phippen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public Interaction: Harry Cutts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Schools and Mentoring: Jeremy Morse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sponsorship: Rob Spanton&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Team Updates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peter Symonds https://pscrobotics.wordpress.com/2015/01/16/cheeky-build-photo/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;QMC http://teamqmc.esy.es/uncategorized/update-2112015/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collyers http://collyersstudentrobotics.blogspot.co.uk/2015/01/keeping-everything-clean-and-tidy.html&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cornwall College Saltash http://ccsrobotics.over-blog.com/2015/01/week-8-recapping-the-code.html&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;KES are still having problems with their kit. Looks like the image wasn't the problem in the end and instead their power board may be faulty.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Tom Leese for working on this issue. The previous issue can be found [here][list-previous-issue].&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2015/2015-02-11-srawn-15.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2015 Issue 16</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2015/2015-02-25-srawn-16.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2015 — 16&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the sixteenth issue of the Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings‐on across Student Robotics. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Internal Updates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The competition dates have been &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/HZAzPaTfYOA/discussion"&gt;finalised&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/gerrit/2253/"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt;. It is happening on 25th and 26th April at Newbury Racecourse (set-up day on 24th).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tech Days in Southampton, Bristol, and Didcot/Oxford &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/wiki/Tech%20Days/Attendance"&gt;have happened&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various issues with &lt;code&gt;SRComp&lt;/code&gt; have been &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/query?status=assigned&amp;amp;status=new&amp;amp;status=release_pending&amp;amp;status=reopened&amp;amp;component=SRComp+suite&amp;amp;or&amp;amp;keywords=~software&amp;amp;status=assigned&amp;amp;status=new&amp;amp;status=release_pending&amp;amp;status=reopened&amp;amp;component=Website&amp;amp;component=Competition&amp;amp;or&amp;amp;keywords=~srcomp&amp;amp;status=assigned&amp;amp;status=new&amp;amp;status=release_pending&amp;amp;status=reopened&amp;amp;group=component&amp;amp;col=id&amp;amp;col=summary&amp;amp;col=status&amp;amp;col=owner&amp;amp;col=type&amp;amp;col=priority&amp;amp;col=milestone&amp;amp;report=21&amp;amp;order=priority"&gt;fixed&lt;/a&gt; and the updated version is &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/wiki/2015/SRCompDeployment"&gt;ready to be deployed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some flags were created using facilities at Southampton for the Tech Days. Andy Barrett-Sprot and Freddie Nash are currently in the process of writing a manufacturing tutorial for them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Giorgos is &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-devel/LEQTr0gQfh8/discussion"&gt;working on&lt;/a&gt; getting the piezoelectric speaker in the power board controllable from user code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Murray is &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/ticket/2831"&gt;working on&lt;/a&gt; a kiosk system to allow webpages to quickly be displayed on kiosks around the venue (including arena displays, league tables, etc.) and easily changed remotely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peter &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/UqlJcglTcQU/discussion"&gt;has (re?)surrected&lt;/a&gt; the idea of having properly defined contacts for each branch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tom and others [are working on] a handbook for volunteers, focusing on mentoring but also covering development. &lt;strong&gt;Contact Tom off-list if you want to be involved.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Team Updates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;KDE have been given a replacement power board.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RHY have dropped out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HRS's power board has been updated to the newer firmware to solve the current limit problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Tom Leese and Murray Colpman for working on this issue. The previous issue can be found &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/OA0LThrRZak/discussion"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2015/2015-02-25-srawn-16.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2015 Issue 17</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2015/2015-03-11-srawn-17.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2015 — 17&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the seventeenth issue of the Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings‐on across Student Robotics. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's only &lt;strong&gt;45&lt;/strong&gt; days until the competition!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Internal Updates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The volunteer form for the competition &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/U2avfua2LVg/discussion"&gt;has been released&lt;/a&gt;. If you would like to come to the competition, &lt;strong&gt;please fill out the &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1IuL0tfRmHNp4gXKKneBj9MpUwRlDV6OAgWBG3aSDz-k/viewform"&gt;volunteer sign up form&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various fixes and improvements to SRComp &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/query?status=assigned&amp;amp;status=new&amp;amp;status=release_pending&amp;amp;status=reopened&amp;amp;component=SRComp+suite&amp;amp;or&amp;amp;keywords=~software&amp;amp;status=assigned&amp;amp;status=new&amp;amp;status=release_pending&amp;amp;status=reopened&amp;amp;component=Website&amp;amp;component=Competition&amp;amp;or&amp;amp;keywords=~srcomp&amp;amp;status=assigned&amp;amp;status=new&amp;amp;status=release_pending&amp;amp;status=reopened&amp;amp;group=component&amp;amp;col=id&amp;amp;col=summary&amp;amp;col=status&amp;amp;col=owner&amp;amp;col=type&amp;amp;col=priority&amp;amp;col=milestone&amp;amp;report=21&amp;amp;order=priority"&gt;have occurred&lt;/a&gt;. A dry run/test day will be happening later this month and if you would like to have your voice heard on what date it happens, &lt;strong&gt;please fill out the &lt;a href="http://doodle.com/aeny6ymfkvsrpuki"&gt;SRComp Dry Run doodle poll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After some flags were created in Southampton, pictures of them &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/wiki/2015/Flags"&gt;have been placed on Trac&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Team Updates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uppingham School (&lt;em&gt;UPP&lt;/em&gt;) are experiencing some &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/forum/viewtopic.php?f=12&amp;amp;t=273"&gt;servo board connection problems&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who helped put this issue together. If you would like, you can also read the &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/ILAzZM0f5Ik/discussion"&gt;previous issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2015/2015-03-11-srawn-17.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2015 Issue 18</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2015/2015-03-25-srawn-18.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2015 — 18&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the eighteenth issue of the Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings‐on across Student Robotics. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's only &lt;strong&gt;31&lt;/strong&gt; days until the competition, make sure you've &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/U2avfua2LVg/discussion"&gt;signed up to volunteer&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Internal Updates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Due to last minute ECS changes, the Southampton &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/IwXUVzX3kbU/discussion"&gt;Vault has been moved&lt;/a&gt; to a new location in the Level 4 Seminar Room in Mountbatten.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/gWHwh2uVc3k/discussion"&gt;layout for the competition has been decided&lt;/a&gt;, and it will basically be the same as last years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A comprehensive &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/wiki/Volunteers/BeginnerTasks"&gt;page containing tasks suitable for beginners&lt;/a&gt; has been created.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/wiki/Tech%20Days/Attendance"&gt;Attendance has been updated&lt;/a&gt; after the Tech Days on the 14th March.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who helped put this issue together. If you would like, you can also read the &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/jAEpPCXcbSo/discussion"&gt;previous issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2015/2015-03-25-srawn-18.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2015 Issue 19</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2015/2015-04-08-srawn-19.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2015 — 19&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the nineteenth issue of the Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings‐on across Student Robotics. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's only &lt;strong&gt;17&lt;/strong&gt; days until the competition, make sure you've &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/U2avfua2LVg/discussion"&gt;signed up to volunteer&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Internal Updates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/2y6lgCOC4Kw/discussion"&gt;venue map&lt;/a&gt; has &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/gerrit/2318"&gt;been published&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Score entry forms &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/ticket/2740"&gt;have been designed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The competition day schedule &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/ticket/2697"&gt;has been decided&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/gerrit/2314"&gt;published on the website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An SRComp Testing day happened and was generally a success. A few issues were discovered, and tickets have been opened for them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General competition preparations are continuing, and &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/pXWYDViv9H8/discussion"&gt;the next two doings at Southampton&lt;/a&gt; will be related to this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who helped put this issue together. If you would like, you can also read the &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/1oglKsIqcEY/discussion"&gt;previous issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2015/2015-04-08-srawn-19.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2015 Issue 20</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2015/2015-04-22-srawn-20.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2015 — 20&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the twentieth issue of the Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings‐on across Student Robotics. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's only &lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; days until the competition! Everyone volunteering at the competition should have received their role assignment and hotel/travel information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Internal Updates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flags &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/ticket/2772"&gt;were built&lt;/a&gt; in Southampton. Adornments have also been bought and will be transported to the competition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everything from Southampton has gone up to Newbury in preparation for the competition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robot markers &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/ticket/2419"&gt;have been updated&lt;/a&gt; for this year's competition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A number of SRComp and SRWeb related patches have been submitted and merged improving the website throughout the competition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Team Updates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A number of teams have unfortunately dropped out, putting the total number of drop outs at 10 currently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look forward to seeing many of you at the competition this weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who helped put this issue together. If you would like, you can also read the &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/o3qJeKaF2Qs/discussion"&gt;previous issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2015/2015-04-22-srawn-20.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2016 Issue 01</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2015-05-06-srawn-01.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2016 — 1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first issue of the 2016 Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings‐on across Student Robotics. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Updates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 2015 competition happened and it was awesome, &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/news/2015-04-28_bws_victorious_sr2015"&gt;congratulations go to the winners&lt;/a&gt; and thanks to all the volunteers who helped out on the day—we hope to see you next year! Photos of the competition &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/1UJ54OKdCVc/discussion"&gt;are being posted&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/groups/sr2015"&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A number of volunteers &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/6E6kkvetqE0/discussion"&gt;have posted their opinions&lt;/a&gt; of how this year’s competition went.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A “News &amp;amp; Events” mailing list &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/RpVXCWEsU_o/discussion"&gt;has been created&lt;/a&gt; to coincide with the first fortnightly newsletter of the 2016 year. The mailing list will contain information regarding upcoming events and related news which I would recommend any volunteer &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/#%21forum/srobo-news"&gt;subscribe to&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various updates to the tools have &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/msg/srobo-devel/NHr2Rmdbj4M/vFJ2uGYPiXMJ"&gt;been merged&lt;/a&gt;. Changes include support for Python 3, virtual environments and a new ‘sr inv-history’ tool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who helped put this issue together. If you would like, you can also read the &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/rtteXYVfsi4/discussion"&gt;previous issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2015-05-06-srawn-01.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2016 Issue 02</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2015-05-20-srawn-02.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2016 — 2&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the second issue of the 2016 Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings‐on across Student Robotics. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The typical lull &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; the storm that is the Student Robotics competition has lead to not an enormous amount happening over the last two weeks. Nevertheless...!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you have any remaining receipts from SR2015, &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/WNFueC8d2Gc/discussion"&gt;make sure you submit them by the 1&amp;lt;sup&amp;gt;st&amp;lt;/sup&amp;gt; June&lt;/a&gt; to ensure you get your money back.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A ticket to start off some discussion about how we write documentation &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/ticket/3066"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;has been opened&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who helped put this issue together. If you would like, you can also read the &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-news/sO-8-g4WhR8/discussion"&gt;previous issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2015-05-20-srawn-02.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2016 Issue 03</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2015-06-03-srawn-03.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2016 — 3&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the third issue of the 2016 Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings‐on across Student Robotics. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Positions for the steering committee have opened up following a number of planned resignations. &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/q_TzJdKI1lA/discussion"&gt;Make sure you get your nominations in by the end of Friday (5&amp;lt;sup&amp;gt;5th&amp;lt;/sup&amp;gt; June)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are a number of no-show schools who have yet to return their kit. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/9hFrL0lrj_g/discussion"&gt;They need chasing after and any help with that would be appreciated.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who helped put this issue together. If you would like, you can also read the &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-news/dQ-wl5fK9Z4/discussion"&gt;previous issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2015-06-03-srawn-03.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2016 Issue 04</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2015-06-17-srawn-04.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2016 — 4&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the fourth issue of the 2016 Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings‐on across Student Robotics. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/msg/srobo/q_TzJdKI1lA/qTA239udxNwJ"&gt;Results from the latest committee elections have been announced&lt;/a&gt; with all roles filled except for Public Interaction. If you would like to go for that role, &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/msg/srobo/q_TzJdKI1lA/AJcZ0V3kq30J"&gt;please put your name forward&lt;/a&gt; by the end of this coming Sunday.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/GoesekPTfcs/discussion"&gt;vote on whether Student Robotics should become a charity&lt;/a&gt; has been opened. &lt;strong&gt;Please take an opportunity to read through the &lt;a href="https://xgoat.com/~rob/sr2016/constitution.pdf"&gt;proposed constitution&lt;/a&gt; and vote.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who helped put this issue together. If you would like, you can also read the &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-news/o7cUGArOVSs/discussion"&gt;previous issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2015-06-17-srawn-04.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2016 Issue 05</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2015-07-01-srawn-05.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2016 — 5&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the fifth issue of the 2016 Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings‐on across Student Robotics. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The community &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/msg/srobo/GoesekPTfcs/T4J0vaH0PYwJ"&gt;has voted for Student Robotics becoming a charity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elections &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/msg/srobo/q_TzJdKI1lA/1kC7yRPBSKMJ"&gt;are open for the position of Public Interaction&lt;/a&gt; in the steering committee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-devel/yHauzU7DxBE/discussion"&gt;Work on the volunteer handbook has continued&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;would appreciated receiving reviews&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who helped put this issue together. If you would like, you can also read the &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-news/SkxCu2P9zls/discussion"&gt;previous issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2015-07-01-srawn-05.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2016 Issue 06</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2015-07-15-srawn-06.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2016 — 6&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the sixth issue of the 2016 Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings‐on across Student Robotics. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;James Thompson has &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/msg/srobo/q_TzJdKI1lA/OsMfJjA-160J"&gt;won the position of Public Interaction&lt;/a&gt; on the steering committee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who helped put this issue together. If you would like, you can also read the &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-news/NLk1wVJ6eCQ/discussion"&gt;previous issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2015-07-15-srawn-06.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2016 Issue 07</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2015-07-29-srawn-07.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2016 — 7&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the seventh issue of the 2016 Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings‐on across Student Robotics. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/wiki/ParticipantStats"&gt;participant stats&lt;/a&gt; have been updated to include details on SR2015.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A ‘Computing and Microelectronics’ course run by the &lt;a href="http://www.smallpeicetrust.org.uk/"&gt;Smallpeice Trust&lt;/a&gt; and utilising Student Robotics kit is under way this week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who helped put this issue together. If you would like, you can also read the &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-news/z3hWkT0due0/discussion"&gt;previous issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2015-07-29-srawn-07.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2016 Issue 08</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2015-08-12-srawn-08.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2016 — 8&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the eighth issue of the 2016 Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings‐on across Student Robotics. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/9hFrL0lrj_g/discussion"&gt;update regarding dealing with teams who didn't show up at the competition has been posted&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-devel/46p1Ie6qYm4/discussion"&gt;Work on the email spam situation has been progressing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who helped put this issue together. If you would like, you can also read the &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-news/QeE_DGXpMjc/discussion"&gt;previous issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2015-08-12-srawn-08.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2016 Issue 09</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2015-08-27-srawn-09.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2016 — 9&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the ninth issue of the 2016 Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings‐on across Student Robotics. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Student Robotics has been &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/BwHyiVSrrbI/discussion"&gt;successfully registered as a charity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a possibility of some media opportunities happening with the BBC in the near future and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/2EUfB5DZNz4/discussion"&gt;any related media items are being collated&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who helped put this issue together. If you would like, you can also read the &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-news/r3Myj_pi5lM/discussion"&gt;previous issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2015-08-27-srawn-09.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2016 Issue 10</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2015-09-09-srawn-10.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2016 — 10&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the tenth issue of the 2016 Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings‐on across Student Robotics. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/wiki/2016/Teams"&gt;list of teams who have put their names down for SR2016&lt;/a&gt; is available on Trac.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/7K40Dp_H7r0/discussion"&gt;Doings in Southampton have started up again&lt;/a&gt; with a large range of activities planned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/-O4LtDJA6ys/discussion"&gt;broadcast date for Student Robotics on BBC Breakfast&lt;/a&gt; has been announced at the 18th September.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/Q8liWoonMlo/discussion"&gt;data visualisations on what kinds of schools we get at the competition&lt;/a&gt; has been put together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/Ngwj3IIYu5s/discussion"&gt;Benchmarking of the website has been happening&lt;/a&gt; in relation to the BBC Breakfast event.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Southampton, &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/S0g3iiuIP4s/discussion"&gt;preparations for fresher recruitment has started&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who helped put this issue together. If you would like, you can also read the &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-news/1fI9aM8LELg/discussion"&gt;previous issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2015-09-09-srawn-10.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2016 Issue 11</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2015-09-23-srawn-11.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2016 — 11&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the eleventh issue of the 2016 Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings‐on across Student Robotics. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We were &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-34288064"&gt;featured on BBC Breakfast&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;a href="https://batchgeo.com/map/bc58cece3eed4eedec56c4ef60078ff6"&gt;map of all the teams taking part in SR2016&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/EreGVPTfUL0/discussion"&gt;has been produced&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/ix5NEnBL_a4/discussion"&gt;a number of improvements to the website&lt;/a&gt; that would be good if they could happen before Kickstart.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/msg/srobo/eH47IeWYTjo/SZ90V779AgAJ"&gt;7th November has been announced&lt;/a&gt; as the date for Kickstart, &lt;strong&gt;this should make its way to the website&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Today there will be a &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/IYrkpLCnNsA/discussion"&gt;doing in Southampton to prepare for fresher recruitment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our server &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/msg/srobo-devel/mV_5AX8bRmU/qTzeoak5BQAJ"&gt;is now running Fedora 22&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who helped put this issue together. If you would like, you can also read the &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-news/-hgYEspbTZE/discussion"&gt;previous issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2015-09-23-srawn-11.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2016 Issue 12</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2015-10-21-srawn-12.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2016 — 12&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;17 days to Kickstart!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/XrwRdzFP-fY"&gt;Future is now!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the twelfth issue of the 2016 Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings‐on across Student Robotics. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The organisation structure for Kickstart &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/RRw7uwopUq0/discussion"&gt;has been announced&lt;/a&gt; and all assets have been transferred to the charity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Power boards and batteries have been taken to Oxford for testing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;code&gt;beep&lt;/code&gt; function &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/gerrit/#/c/2500/"&gt;has been added to the power board Python API&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An outline has been put together for the Kickstart microgames.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who helped put this issue together. If you would like, you can also read the &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-news/4OdWiwY-H2g/discussion"&gt;previous issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2015-10-21-srawn-12.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2016 Issue 13</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2015-11-04-srawn-13.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2016 — 13&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3 days to Kickstart!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the thirteenth issue of the 2016 Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings‐on across Student Robotics. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The kit has been packed and distributed to the various Kickstart locations. Thanks go to everyone who helped with this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The date for the first Bristol tech day &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/events/sr2016/2015-12-12-bristol_tech_day_1"&gt;has been added to the website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The dates for the &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/gerrit/#/c/2554/"&gt;Southampton tech days&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/gerrit/#/c/2542/"&gt;first Oxford tech day&lt;/a&gt; will be on the website shortly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The location of the London Kickstart had to &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/OdfrRa3yp3g/discussion"&gt;be changed at the last minute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/3pBR_XF4vTI/discussion"&gt;Oxford Outreach Meetup event is happening in early December&lt;/a&gt; for those who are interested.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/lE4MEjpnYG4/discussion"&gt;Southampton branch is now affiliated with the University of Southampton's Students Union&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-game/-m845hF2Ar0/discussion"&gt;Discussion of this year's game continues&lt;/a&gt; in the private game mailing list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who helped put this issue together. If you would like, you can also read the &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-news/rnO7X7tLZBw/discussion"&gt;previous issue&lt;/a&gt;.

&amp;quot;10 things are infinite in this world, human stupidity, and binary numbers....&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2015-11-04-srawn-13.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2016 Issue 14</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2015-11-18-srawn-14.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2016 — 14&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the fourteenth issue of the 2016 Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings‐on across Student Robotics. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/Eg7WWpq1Da4/discussion"&gt;interactive 3D token website&lt;/a&gt; has been created.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kickstart happened and was very successful! Thanks go to everyone who helped and we hope you enjoyed the day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are plans for an activity day in place and we're looking for &lt;a href="http://doodle.com/poll/znst2ab2weh3tw3r"&gt;people to submit what day they would like best&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-devel/mbYhTq2KGRo/discussion"&gt;was a bug in the naming of the markers in the robot code&lt;/a&gt; which has been fixed and shipped.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who helped put this issue together. If you would like, you can also read the &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-news/gSx0PGyHESw/discussion"&gt;previous issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2015-11-18-srawn-14.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2016 Issue 15</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2015-12-02-srawn-15.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2016 — 15&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the fifteenth issue of the 2016 Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings‐on across Student Robotics. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LHS and MEA &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/wiki/2016/Teams?version=43"&gt;have been dropped out&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WGS &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/trac/wiki/2016/Teams?version=44"&gt;have been given a position&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who helped put this issue together. If you would like, you can also read the &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-news/66HRe__zdfg/discussion"&gt;previous issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2015-12-02-srawn-15.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2016 Issue 16</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2016-01-20-srawn-16.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2016 — 16&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the sixteenth issue of the 2016 Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings‐on across Student Robotics. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apologies for the delay from the last newsletter, the Christmas break combined with exams has given us a break without reconvening&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christmas and new year happened!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mentors have been allocated in Southampton, and will start mentoring their teams soon!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Student Robotics Volunteer activity day 2016 has been announced, and there is a &lt;a href="http://doodle.com/poll/fnskxi2ykaddh45s"&gt;doodle poll&lt;/a&gt; to find the most convenient date.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who helped put this issue together. If you would like, you can also read the &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-news/HXMqpOP7IgM/discussion"&gt;previous issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2016-01-20-srawn-16.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2016 Issue 17</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2016-02-03-srawn-17.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2016 — 17&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the seventeenth issue of the 2016 Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings‐on across Student Robotics. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;George Field has created a &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/msg/srobo/WnVig4Ie1mM/fytJ3b2sFAAJ"&gt;token/arena cheatsheet&lt;/a&gt; to help competitors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/AYySaAgsIG0/discussion"&gt;date for the activity day has been announced as the 13th February&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/gerrit/#/c/2602/"&gt;email about the London tech day has been sent out to teams&lt;/a&gt;, and as a consequence to this, there has already been two sign-ups for the tech day in Southampton.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who helped put this issue together. If you would like, you can also read the &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-news/JAwfc42CNdk/discussion"&gt;previous issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2016-02-03-srawn-17.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2016 Issue 18</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2016-02-17-srawn-18.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2016 — 18&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the eighteenth issue of the 2016 Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings‐on across Student Robotics. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A first draft of the Ops Manual has been &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/OyZMQ8xVlEc/discussion"&gt;published on the mailing list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An Activity Day happened in Southampton and some people have &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/#%21topic/srobo/2KWH6r4iEjc"&gt;spoken about it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A list of &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/#%21topic/srobo/1PGbwKFDsM0"&gt;teams on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; has been compiled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An initial form for announcing &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/#%21topic/srobo/kyJ9WKfqViQ"&gt;interest to helping at the competition&lt;/a&gt; has been released.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The date and location for the competition &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/d8jMxfXA5Cs/discussion"&gt;has been announced as the 30th April at Newbury Racecourse&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who helped put this issue together. If you would like, you can also read the &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-news/uS0sYmUUxM0/discussion"&gt;previous issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2016-02-17-srawn-18.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2016 Issue 19</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2016-03-03-srawn-19.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2016 — 19&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the nineteenth issue of the 2016 Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings‐on across Student Robotics. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/#%21topic/srobo/wsJrHe_VdJ8"&gt;more videos&lt;/a&gt; have been created. Notably one for &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/1nuQV77-_x4"&gt;how to use the tablet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Tech Day in Southampton last Saturday was very successful. The teams worked on their robots and made the most of the help offered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who helped put this issue together. If you would like, you can also read the &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-news/saKgm_ZpPEQ/discussion"&gt;previous issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2016-03-03-srawn-19.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2016 Issue 20</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2016-03-16-srawn-20.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2016 — 20&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the twentieth issue of the 2016 Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings‐on across Student Robotics. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Southampton Branch has hosted an AGM today, the results of which &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-soton/aJOhKwq8Tjg/discussion"&gt;have been published in this blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/msg/srobo-game/wQv_JP0cCG0/CMMzYkgDFwAJ"&gt;Some discussion about whether robots can perform actions before start signal&lt;/a&gt; has happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/msg/srobo/Vp_uPbpZpzM/6vTGT-xYCQAJ"&gt;BDF would like some electronics help&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;if you're in the Bedford area, it would be good to let us know&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Peter has started the ball rolling on both &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-devel/HNzXwNShnK0/discussion"&gt;the scoresheet design&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-devel/cBmB_vm5byQ/discussion"&gt;the competition software for SR2016&lt;/a&gt;, the latter of which he's given a deadline for modifications of the weekend of the 16th April.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who helped put this issue together. If you would like, you can also read the &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-news/w4ueDzEijo4/discussion"&gt;previous issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2016-03-16-srawn-20.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2016 Issue 21</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2016-03-30-srawn-21.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2016 — 21&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the twenty first issue of the 2016 Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings‐on across Student Robotics. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One month to go until the competition!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jeremy has &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/RuRNplPSgSQ/discussion"&gt;requested help dealing with media consent forms&lt;/a&gt;. He may have enough volunteers now although if you are up for it, it would be good to let him know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo/bp1ERhRAiuY/discussion"&gt;reflection on the well-received tech day that happened in Southampton&lt;/a&gt; on the 19th March has been posted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-devel/Su2wAuB7JHo/discussion"&gt;Discussion on how mock arenas could be built&lt;/a&gt; in the future has been started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who helped put this issue together. If you would like, you can also read the &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-news/lmfGB-rrgh8/discussion"&gt;previous issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2016-03-30-srawn-21.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2016 Issue 22</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2016-04-27-srawn-22.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2016 — 22&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the twenty second issue of the 2016 Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings‐on across Student Robotics. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only two days to go until the competition!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Media consent forms have been processed by a number of volunteers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kit stored in Southampton has been moved to Newbury for the competition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work has been done on improving the Student Robotics competition software to suit the next competition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The committee &lt;a href="https://bitbucket.org/srobo/ops-manual/wiki/Home"&gt;has created a tree of links to documents for the operations manual&lt;/a&gt; for all documentation in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who helped put this issue together. If you would like, you can also read the &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/topic/srobo-news/zpUI1aFcN0Q/discussion"&gt;previous issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2016/2016-04-27-srawn-22.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2017 Issue 03</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2017/2016-06-15-srawn-03.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2017 -- 3&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the third issue of the 2017 Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings‐on across Student Robotics. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Headlines&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/#%21topic/srobo-game/-SNXPWVv8_M"&gt;Games&lt;/a&gt; for next year's competition have started to be suggested. &lt;strong&gt;If you have access to the thread feel free to contribute your ideas.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It has been a slow (almost) week at Student Robotics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jimmy Thompson has been working on a &lt;a href="https://srobo.github.io/style/"&gt;new Style Guide&lt;/a&gt; for the logo, and an &lt;a href="https://srobo.github.io/website/"&gt;entirely new website&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/msg/srobo/fho0shyhFxM/4HLBNMtzAwAJ"&gt;has asked for feedback&lt;/a&gt; in the mailing list.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There has been &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/msg/srobo/-l4vxh7clo4/fFxLHfCCAQAJ"&gt;continued discussion&lt;/a&gt; about whether the new private &lt;a href="https://studentrobotics.slack.com/"&gt;slack group&lt;/a&gt; should allow competitors to join.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who helped put this issue together. If you would like, you can also read the &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/#%21topic/srobo/yH5ms8BS52U"&gt;previous issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2017/2016-06-15-srawn-03.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2017 Issue 06</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2017/2016-06-15-srawn-06.html</link><description>&lt;h1&gt;SR(A)WN 2017 -- 6&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the sixth issue of the 2017 Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter, a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings‐on across Student Robotics. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones which we believe could do with extra hands. An absence of emboldening does not necessarily mean that everything is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Headlines&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/news/2016-10-06-sr2017-kickstart-dates-announced/"&gt;Kickstart&lt;/a&gt; was held in &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/events/sr2017/southampton-kickstart/"&gt;Southampton&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/events/sr2017/oxford-kickstart/"&gt;Oxford&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/events/sr2017/bristol-kickstart/"&gt;Bristol&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href="https://studentrobotics.org/docs/resources/2017/rulebook.pdf"&gt;Game&lt;/a&gt; for this year's competition has been announced at kickstart. (Easy as ABC)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A problem with the tablets means that some tablets have no shortcut to their robot's web interface, &lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/forum/598"&gt;leading to confusion among teams&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1SxYuUYd_N1_aad55BsQ1NIAZNcHo_Jp6qevUld5Em7g/viewform?edit_requested=true#start=invite"&gt;mentor sign up form&lt;/a&gt; which potential mentors should fill in to get information on mentoring.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.studentrobotics.org/forum/611"&gt;GDC has claimed first movement&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;it is currently unclear if they are a rookie team.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Minor Headlines&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The volunteers in Southampton have permananently moved to &lt;a href="https://studentrobotics.slack.com/"&gt;The SR Slack&lt;/a&gt; for all communications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who helped put this issue together. If you would like, you can also read the &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/d/msg/srobo/R0klOD2wW6A/b2_zJtRcAQAJ"&gt;previous issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2017/2016-06-15-srawn-06.html</guid></item><item><title>SR2021 Issue 01</title><link>https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2021/2020-12-20-srawn-01.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Student Robotics (Almost) Weekly Newsletter is a (roughly) fortnightly newsletter which summarises the goings‐on across Student Robotics. &lt;strong&gt;Emboldened&lt;/strong&gt; items are ones for which additional help has been requested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Headlines&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;SR(A)WN is back for SR2021!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a 1417 day hiatus, SR(A)WN is back to keep you updated on news and developments within Student Robotics. (Still almost weekly, right?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep up with SR(A)WN:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join the &lt;code&gt;#srawn&lt;/code&gt; channel on &lt;a href="https://app.slack.com/client/T0EEPF1LH/C01GBT8NMSN"&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;recommended&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join the &lt;code&gt;srawn&lt;/code&gt; mailing list on &lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/g/srawn"&gt;Google Groups&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read historical issues on the &lt;a href="https://studentrobotics.org/srawn"&gt;SR(A)WN Archive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Holiday Social&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the &lt;em&gt;24th December 17:00 - 20:00 UTC&lt;/em&gt; we will be having a festive social. We'll likely be playing some games (Among Us, Jackbox etc.) but nothing has been decided yet so shout if there's something you really want to do. The Google Meet link will be in &lt;a href="https://studentrobotics.slack.com/archives/CF94T25GU"&gt;&lt;code&gt;#social&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on Slack if you want to join!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Discord&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're experimenting with using Discord this year as opposed to the forums. If you'd like to join and help answer questions or just join in the banter with the teams, the sign up link is &lt;a href="https://studentrobotics.slack.com/archives/C0EEJ0ASY/p1607552491072100"&gt;pinned&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;code&gt;#general&lt;/code&gt; on Slack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New Trustee&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomas Scarsbrook (better known as Scarzy) has joined David and Diane on the Board of Trustees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Competition&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Game&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our game this year, &lt;a href="https://studentrobotics.org/docs/rules/"&gt;Radars of the Lost Ark&lt;/a&gt;, challenges teams to score points by claiming territories using radios. Teams must navigate the arena scanning for tower transmissions and sending their own transmissions back to claim territories. Teams are awarded points at the end of the match for the maximum extent of their territory at any one time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Game Modules&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As this competition year doesn’t feature a physical competition event, the structure of the competition has changed. The league matches will take place on four weekends throughout the year. After each league session the game will gain additional modules that will present new and different challenges to the competitors. If you have any cool ideas for modules please share them in &lt;code&gt;#game&lt;/code&gt; on Slack or come along to a Competition Meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Competition Meetings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have weekly Competition meetings on Thursdays at 8:30, these are open to all so feel free to drop in without notice or on an ad-hoc basis. These meetings, and any others, can be found on the &lt;a href="https://studentrobotics.org/runbook/volunteering/calendars/"&gt;volunteer calendar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Friendlies Matches for Teams&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're looking to organise friendly matches for the teams to have a chance to test their code in a less stressful environment. A chance for competitors to face off against other teams, socialize, and get some support from blueshirts. These will be happening 1 week before each league session at 10:30.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Webots Update&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Webots, the simulation software behind the competition simulator, released version 2021a with breaking changes. &lt;a href="https://github.com/srobo/competition-simulator/pull/251"&gt;A fix&lt;/a&gt; has been submitted to the simulator so that 2020b and 2021a should both work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Kit&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Brain Updates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Brain Team is re-developing SR kit software for the SR2022 cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We have started working on replacements for the legacy software currently used with the SR kit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We now have developed an MVP replacement for herdsman called &lt;a href="https://github.com/srobo/astoria"&gt;Astoria&lt;/a&gt;, which uses asynchronous Python and JSON over MQTT. This software primarily handles detecting and loading student code from USB drives. &lt;a href="https://srobo.github.io/astoria"&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt; is now available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We have also begun development on a new &lt;a href="https://github.com/srobo/robot-base"&gt;Debian-based system image&lt;/a&gt;, which we aim to build for both ODROID and Raspberry Pi boards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://studentrobotics.org/srawn/SR2021/2020-12-20-srawn-01.html</guid></item></channel></rss>